Guide to the Burdette Keeland Architectural Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Architectural Projects - Drawings
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 34)
    - 1912 West Capitol Building - Working Drawings (Prints), 1964 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 34, Item 1)
    - Sketch of Maher House by Howard Barnstone, approximately 1964 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 34, Item 2)
  - 1912 West Capitol Building - Presentation Drawing by Eugene Aubry, 1964 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 35)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36)
    - Green Residence - Working Drawings, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36, Item 1)
    - Edgecomb Residence - Working Drawings, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36, Item 2)
    - Butler Residence Additions - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36, Item 3)
    - Gaines Residence - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36, Item 4)
    - Office Plan (unknown), undated (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 36, Item 5)
  - IBM Office Building, Beaumont, TX - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1964-1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 37)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 38)
    - Office Building for Burdette Keeland, Jr. - Working Drawings, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 38, Item 1)
    - Bank of Texas Offices - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 38, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 39)
    - Shopping Center, Richmond Ave. - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 39, Item 1)
    - Holmes Shopping Center - Working Drawings, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 39, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 40)
    - Spring Branch Savings & Loan - Proposed Addition, Preliminary Drawings, 1965-1966 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 40, Item 1)
    - Meat Processors Center - Preliminary Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 40, Item 2)
    - Biddle Residence - Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 40, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 41)
    - Horne Beach House - Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 41, Item 1)
    - Union Hall, I.L.A. Local #1330 - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 41, Item 2)
    - Allen Residence - Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 41, Item 3)
  - Houghton Residence, La Grange, TX - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 42)
  - Flight Instruction School for Thomas Holmes - Working Drawings, 1965-1966 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 43)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 44)
    - Davis Weekend House - Working Drawings, 1965 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 44, Item 1)
    - Danziger Commercial Building - Working Drawings, 1966 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 44, Item 2)
    - Commercial Building for Lafayette Herring - Working Drawings, undated (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 44, Item 3)
    - Chateau Bissonnet Apartments - Working Drawings, 1965-1966 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 44, Item 4)
  - Woodland Acres Church of Christ - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1967-1968 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 45)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 46)
    - Plan for Contemporary Arts Association Exhibit, 1964 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 46, Item 1)
    - Miscellaneous Presentation Drawings, mid 1960s (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 46, Item 2)
    - Washington on the Brazos State Park - Preliminary Drawings, approximately late 1960s (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 46, Item 3)
    - Lander Weekend House - Working Drawings, 1966 (Drawer 4, Ovs folder 46, Item 4)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 47)
    - Fox Residence - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1966 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 47, Item 1)
    - Williams Beach House - Working Drawings, 1967 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 47, Item 2)
    - Sunset Blvd. Clinic Remodel - Working Drawings, 1969 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 47, Item 3)
  - Oxford Place Apartments - Working Drawings, 1968-1969 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 48)
  - Oxford Place Apartments - Working Drawings, 1968-1969 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 49)
  - Bank of Texas Kiosk - Working Drawings, 1970-1971 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 50)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 51)
    - Loggins Residence - Lake Travis, Preliminary Drawings, 1970 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 51, Item 1)
    - Masterson Residence Addition - Working Drawings, 1972–1973 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 51, Item 2)
    - Spring Branch Savings & Loan Addition - Working Drawings, 1971-1972 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 51, Item 3)
  - Kipling Townhouses - Working Drawings (prints), approximately 1974 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 52)
  - Barkdull Townhouses - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1974 (Drawer 5, Ovs folder 53)
  - Holly Hall Activities Building - Working Drawings (prints), 1974 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 54)
  - Southern State Bank Drive-in Banking Facilities - Working Drawings (prints), 1974 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 55)
  - Williams Retirement House - Preliminary Drawings, approximately late 1960s (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 56)
  - Grace Townhouses - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1972 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 57)
  - Keeland Residence, 2907 Ferndale St. - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1976-1982 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 58)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 59)
    - Bakery for Jean Pierre - Working Drawings, approximately mid 1960s (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 59, Item 1)
    - 4101 Greenbriar Professional Building - Preliminary Drawings, 1975 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 59, Item 2)
    - Maurer Engineering Offices - Preliminary Drawings, 1977 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 59, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 60)
    - Tucson Project - Preliminary Drawings, 1981 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 60, Item 1)
    - T.J. Holmes Residence Addition - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1980 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 60, Item 2)
  - 4141 Greenbriar Building - Presentation Drawings (not by Keeland), 1983 (Drawer 6, Ovs folder 61)
  - Katy Horse Farm - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1983 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 62)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 63)
    - Dr. Hablinski Offices - Working Drawings, 1988 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 63, Item 1)
    - Kaplan-Keeland Residence Remodel, Austin, TX - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1990 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 63, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 64)
    - Hermann Drive Expansion - Preliminary Drawings, 1991 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 64, Item 1)
    - Keeland Entry - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1992 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 64, Item 2)
  - Keeland Beach House - Preliminary Drawings, 1991-1992 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 65)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 66)
    - Meyerland Parade of Homes House Alterations - Working Drawings (prints), 1995 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 66, Item 1)
    - Adams Garage and Apartment, Denver, CO - Working Drawings, ca. 1996 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 66, Item 2)
  - Garrett Residence Remodel (Parade of Homes House) - Preliminary Drawings, 1995 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 67)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 68)
    - Elliott Bay House - Preliminary Drawings, 1995 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 68, Item 1)
    - Hill Residence, Blanco, TX - Preliminary Drawings, 1996 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 68, Item 2)
  - Cedarvale Cemetery, Bay City, TX - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1996 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 69)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 70)
    - Miscellaneous Studies and Sketches, approximately 1950s (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 70, Item 1)
    - Miscellaneous Presentation Drawings, approximately 1950s (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 70, Item 2)
  - Studies, Residential Project - Preliminary Drawings, 1957 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 71)
  - Studies, Residential Project - Preliminary Drawings, 1959 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 72)
  - Student Work, Yale University, 1959-1960 (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous Renderings (residential), 1950s (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 74)
  - Miscellaneous Renderings (commercial, office), 1950s (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 75)
  - Miscellaneous Renderings (apartment buildings), 1950s (Drawer 7, Ovs folder 76)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Keeland Student Work - Presentation Boards, 1940s-1950s (Drawer 8, Ovs folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Keeland Student Work - Presentation Boards, 1940s-1950s (Drawer 8, Ovs folder 78)
  - Miscellaneous Projects - Presentation Boards, 1950s (Drawer 8, Ovs folder 79)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Presentation Boards (5), 1955 (Drawer 9, Ovs folder 80)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Presentation Boards (2), 1955 (Drawer 9, Ovs folder 81)
  - Gilbert Arnold House - Presentation Boards (4), 1955 (Drawer 9, Ovs folder 82)
  - Oxford Place Apartments - Presentation Boards, 1968-1969 (Drawer 9, Ovs folder 83)
  - Kaplan-Keeland Residence Remodel, Austin, TX - Presentation Boards, 1990 (Drawer 9, Ovs folder 84)
  - Historical Subjects - Presentation Boards, undated (Drawer 10, Ovs folder 85)
  - Shields Office Building - Presentation Boards, 1955 (Drawer 10, Ovs folder 86)
  - Spring Branch Savings & Loan - Presentation Boards, 1957 (Drawer 10, Ovs folder 87)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 88)
    - Memorial Bend Club - Presentation Boards, 1959 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 88, Item 1)
    - 2721 Kipling Apartments - Presentation Boards, 1953 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 88, Item 2)
    - Williams Beach House - Presentation Boards, 1967 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 88, Item 3)
  - Essex-Houck Building - Presentation Boards, 1961 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 89)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 90)
    - 4101 Greenbriar Professional Building - Presentation Boards, 1975 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 90, Item 1)
    - 4141 Greenbriar Building - Presentation Boards, 1983 (Drawer 11, Ovs folder 90, Item 2)
  - City Planning Commission Materials, approximately 1982 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 91)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 92)
    - Map, Keeland Travels, approximately 1996 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 92, Item 1)
    - “Famous Toilets” Studio Project, 1981 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 92, Item 2)
    - “Ronchamps” Student Drawing, undated (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 92, Item 3)
  - Notre Dame Cathedral, Paris, by Alex Wong, print mounted on masonite board, 1965 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 93)
  - Original Art, tempera on board, artist unknown, (total 2), 1969 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 94)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 95)
    - Artwork for tomb sales brochure by Rosner, Wong, Fowler, 1995 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 95, Item 1)
    - Philip Johnson collage by Burdette Keeland, 1991 (Drawer 12, Ovs folder 95, Item 2)
  - Artwork and material for Keeland cemetery book, 1990s (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 96)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 97)
    - Presentation board from “Ten Years Out” exhibition at Yale, 1995 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 97, Item 1)
    - Enlargement of Keeland beach house design from Keeland exhibition at UH College of Architecture, 2000 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 97, Item 2)
  - Architecture Posters (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 98)
    - Architecture Posters, undated (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 98, Item 1)
    - Knoll Salutes University of Cincinnati, 1996 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 98, Item 2)
    - University of Cincinnati, College of Design, undated (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 98, Item 3)
    - Michael Graves, Recent Work, University of Cincinnati, 1996 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 98, Item 4)
  - UH Architecture Posters (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99)
    - Blueprint Ball, UH College of Architecture, 1998 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99, Item 1)
    - Why, Houston, Why? UH College of Architecture, 1984 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99, Item 2)
    - A Celebration of Architecture, UH College of Architecture (dedication of new building), 1986 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99, Item 3)
    - V from Building X, UH College of Architecture lectures, 1996 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99, Item 4)
    - Keeland Exhibition, UH College of Architecture, 2000 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 99, Item 5)
  - 18th and 19th century engravings acquired by Keeland on his travels (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100)
    - "Windsor", 1792 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 1)
    - "Lake of Perugia", 1792 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 2)
    - "Perugia", 1793 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 3)
    - "Geneve" (modern reprint) (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 4)
    - Arch of Constantine, approximately 1699 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 5)
    - Temple of Neptune, approximately 1699 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 6)
    - "Les Petites Marionettes", approximately 1800 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 7)
    - Untitled French scene, approximately 1800 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 8)
    - "Richmond, Surrey", 1821 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 9)
    - "Ripon, Yorkshire", 1821 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 10)
    - "Lymouth, N. Devon", 1821 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 11)
    - "Sida fragrans" [plants] by Redoute, approximately 1785 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 100, Item 12)
  - 18th and 19th century engravings acquired by Keeland on his travels (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101)
    - "Shepherds," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 1)
    - "Winter," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 2)
    - "George, Earl McCartney," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 3)
    - "William Duke of Leinster," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 4)
    - "A Snake in the Grass," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 5)
    - "William Lord Mansfield," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 6)
    - "George, Duke of Marlboro," Joshua Reynolds, 1824 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 7)
    - Nobleman, after Hans Holbein, approximately 1812 (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 8)
    - Noblewoman, artist unknown, undated (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 9)
    - Nobleman, artist unknown, undated (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 101, Item 10)
- Art Posters, 1944-1995
  Keeland had a large collection of art posters, most acquired from the 1960s to 1980s during his travels.
  - Art Posters mounted on board, undated (Drawer 13, Ovs folder 102)
  - Art Prints, originals (3) (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 103)
    - "1972 Puzzle" by Michael Herd, 1971 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 103, Item 1)
    - "#3" by Francisca Duran R., 1968 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 103, Item 2)
    - Loving Spoonful Album art by Philip Hays, approximately 1969 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 103, Item 3)
  - Ernest Trova, Recent Sculpture, Pace Gallery, New York, mounted on board, 1967 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 104)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105)
    - Freud Has a Better Idea, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 1)
    - Marisol, Museum Boymans-van Beuningen, Rotterdam, 1968 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 2)
    - Kline, Sidney Janis Gallery, New York, 1958 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 3)
    - Picasso, Les Pigeons, Netherlands, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 4)
    - Cobra, Louisiana, Danish museum, 1966 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 5)
    - Yves Klein, Louisiana, Danish museum, 1968 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 6)
    - Edward Ruscha/Kenneth Price/Joe Goode, Museum Boymans-van Beuningen, Rotterdam, 1972 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 7)
    - Salvador Dali, Museum Boymans-van Beuningen, Rotterdam, n.d. (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 8)
    - Bonjour Mourlot, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1973 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 9)
    - The Great Decade of American Abstraction: Modernist Art, 1960–1970, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston (Inaugural exhibition of the Brown Pavilion), 1974 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 105, Item 10)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106)
    - Pierre-Humbert, Galerie Roque, Paris, 1972 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 1)
    - Scott Burton, Tate Gallery, London, 1985 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 2)
    - Paul McCartney poster, 1974 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 3)
    - Marc Chagall a Palazzo Pitti, Palazzo Pitti, Florence, 1978 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 4)
    - Nay, Nationalgalerie Berlin, 1969 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 5)
    - Frank Sinatra poster, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 6)
    - 1972 calendar poster, Michael Herd, 1971 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 7)
    - 1974 calendar poster, Michael Herd, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 8)
    - 1975 calendar poster, Michael Herd, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 9)
    - 1976 calendar poster, Michael Herd (mounted on board), undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 10)
    - SKMP2 di Luca Patella, l’attico, Rome, 1968 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 106, Item 11)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107)
    - Reproduction print by Ruffino Tamayo, 1944 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 1)
    - Texas Zephyr, Christmas Card, Dave Schumacher, undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 2)
    - American Art at Mid Century, National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C., 1978 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 3)
    - La Rime et la Raison, Menil Collection Exhibition, Grand Palais, Paris, 1984 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 4)
    - Illustrated Map of Scotland, 1979 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 5)
    - Large laminated collage (possibly by Keeland), undated (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 6)
    - Laumeier Sculpture Park: First Decade, St. Louis, 1986 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 7)
    - Spirits Break Free with Mental Growth, Houston International Hospital, 1988 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 8)
    - Louise Nevelson, Allen Center, Houston, 1983 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 9)
    - Warhol, Tate Gallery, London, 1971 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 107, Item 10)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108)
    - Picasso, Palais des Papes, Paris, 1973 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 1)
    - Foultitude, Musee des Arts Decoratifs, Paris, 1969 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 2)
    - David Smith, Guggenheim Museum, New York, 1969 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 3)
    - Henry Moore, MOMA, New York, 1983 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 4)
    - Generations, Kelsey Seybold Clinic, Houston, 1989 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 5)
    - Charles Giulioli, Schlumberger Gallery, Santa Rosa, CA, 1987 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 6)
    - Ed Baynard, Meredith Gallery, Baltimore, 1982 (Drawer 14, Ovs folder 108, Item 7)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 109)
    - Henry Moore, Orangerie des Tuleries, Paris (mounted on board), 1977 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 109, Item 1)
    - Michael Moon/John Latham, Tate Gallery, London (mounted on board), 1976 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 109, Item 2)
    - Magritte poster (mounted on board), undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 109, Item 3)
    - Picasso poster (mounted on board), undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 109, Item 4)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110)
    - Lenin poster, undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 1)
    - Soviet workers poster, 1974 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 2)
    - Soviet students poster, 1974 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 3)
    - Moscow travel poster, 1995 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 4)
    - Toledo, Corpus Christi, Spain, 1977 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 5)
    - American Women on the Move, National Women’s Conference, Houston, TX, 1977 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 6)
    - From the Lady Poets of Texas, National Women’s Conference, Houston, TX, 1977 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 110, Item 7)
  - Art Posters (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111)
    - Love (multiple languages) on fabric, undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 1)
    - Ninon de Beauval, Art Noveau poster reproduction, Vienna, undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 2)
    - Fromme, Nallendar, Art Noveau poster reproduction, Vienna, undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 3)
    - Bande Dessinee et Figuration Narrative, Musee des Arts Decoratifs, Paris, 1967 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 4)
    - Vincent van Gogh, Orangerie des Tuleries, Paris, 1972 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 5)
    - Jurgen Klein, Ambivalente Flachen, Nurnberg, 1969 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 6)
    - On the Leading Edge, Tony Robbin, Rice University, 1982 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 7)
    - Naïve Paintings from Yugoslavia, Kunsthalle Nurnberg, 1968 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 8)
    - Victor Vasarely, Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam, 1966 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 9)
    - Tate Makes Friends, Tate Gallery, London, undated (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 111, Item 10)
  - Competition Entry, Sesquicentennial Park, Wortham Center, 1987 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 112)
  - Abstract watercolor painting by Gertrude Barnstone, 1964 (Drawer 15, Ovs folder 113)
- Oversized Rolled Materials, 1966-1996
  Those items too large to fit in an oversized flat file are stored in rolled form.
  - Calvert Future (for Town of Calvert, Texas) Presentation Drawing (36” x 86”), approximately mid 1960s (Ovs tube 1, Item 1)
  - Rosenquist, et al., Kunshalle Bern (50” x 36”), 1966 (Ovs tube 2, Item 1)
  - Live in your Head, Kunshalle Bern (50” x 36”), 1969 (Ovs tube 2, Item 2)
  - Matisse, Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam, undated (Ovs tube 2, Item 3)
  - Mondrian, Haags Gemeentemuseum (48” x 34”), undated (Ovs tube 2, Item 4)
  - National Building Museum, undated (Ovs tube 2, Item 5)
  - The Machine, Rice University (inaugural exhibition at Rice gallery), 1969 (Ovs tube 2, Item 6)
  - Large graphics from Incunabula exhibit, 1996 (Ovs tube 3-5)
- Oversized framed artwork, 1980
  - Patrick Procktor, Forbidden City, Beijing framed color aquatint (stored on wall in office, Special Collections), 1980 (Ovs item 1)
- Oversized sign, 1984-1986
  - Construction sign, University of Houston Architecture Building (stored on wall in stacks, Special Collections), 1984-1986 (Ovs item 1)